pcutilitiespro.com 2017-11-25

# PC Utilities Pro - Privacy Policy

As you may know, engaging in business may require the exchange of information between the parties participating in business. Fully described herewith is our site's Privacy Policy describing the information we may collect, the reason behind it, how we use it, and how we protect your information as yourself, the consumer.

## The information we collect and the reason behind it:

##### Details for registering, downloading, and purchasing:

In order to access specific areas of our website (especially downloading or purchasing), you will initially be requested to fill in a detailed form in order to download the free trial version of the software or to form an account prior to purchasing any of the products on our site. 

##### Registration:

During the process of the registration, The User will be requested to submit their contact details and information such as; full name, post address, email address, detailed payment method information, and will be asked to select a unique password for the account created. Your email address will be used as your ‘username’ if and when requested to sign in or activate the software. We email all of our newly registered users and customers with an instructional email greeting. This is done in order to verify the password and username. It’s very important that when you submit your email address, make sure that it is an active and working one. This is going to be the email address where you will receive email notifications from us containing your download links, purchase confirmation, activation keys, support, product notices, and any relevant updates regarding transactions executed by you.

##### Purchase:

When purchasing one of our products, we ask for your full contact details along with your billing and personal address information. This information will be used for processing the order, receiving the payment information through the credit card processing and verification process, and to deliver the goods you have selected and purchased. Should there be a problem with any order, one of our representatives may contact you via email or phone in order to clarify. Remember that the confirmation email of each purchase and transaction is sent to the exact address you gave us, so make sure it is correct.

##### Download:

When downloading a free trial version from one of the software programs or any full version software, you will be requested for your contact information and email address. You may get email messages from us that relate to any transaction. The email subjects may include download referral links, activation software information, help & support alerts, and upgrades for the software full version with updates included.

We also collect technical information about your computer in order to carry out the software Service. This includes your IP Address, browser type, operating system version, GUID identification, and customer configuration. Your technical information is associated with your personal account. This information is used to understand the correct configuration for your computer, what your actual configuration contains, in order to carry out the functions of the Service that you have selected. Note: We do not make copies of your program or data files on your computer to perform the Service.

##### Why do we collect your personal information:

We collect personal information:

  * To conduct repairs and maintenance on your computer as requested by you
  * To perform archive and restoration activities requested by you
  * Newsletter subscriptions
  * Personalization of the user experience on the software
  * Scientific research and improvement of the Service
  * To notify you of our new services or changes to our existing Services
  * To send you technical or service-related communications
  * To enforce the Terms of Service

## What we do with the information collected:

##### Subscribing to PCUtilitiesPro.com Special Offers:

When you submit the email address, you will be given an option to "opt-in" to A PCUtilitiesPro.com promotional newsletter. By agreeing to receive these notifications from us, we will be regularly sending you emails containing relevant product and service information such as; new product releases, updates, and upgrade information, including any special offers that we think may be relevant to you.

##### Unsubscribing from A newsletter: 

Should you wish to stop receiving these email communications, please use the "unsubscribe" feature mentioned in the emails or you can send an email asking to be removed from the newsletters. When you actually “unsubscribe” using the links from the email or from the site, we guarantee to be removing your email address from our newsletter database list. This will usually take place prior to the upcoming additional mailing. Furthermore, from this time on, you will not receive our newsletter email communications. _  Please note that in case you have purchased a product or downloaded a free trial version prior to this, or if you decide to purchase again or download again after you have already unsubscribed from our mailings, we may send you service emails strictly related to these actions. The emails may include notifications such as product notices, order confirmations, expiry alerts, security notifications, or compatibility notifications._

##### Preserving Your Privacy – We do not allow the sharing of any information: 

PCUtilitiesPro.com is the only owner of any related information that is collected on this website. We are strictly against selling, disclosing, or renting the information collected here within this site to any third parties unless if in a case we will be required to by a binding agreement or by a legal proceeding or any law.

##### While visiting different websites: 

Our website may contain hyper links to other internet properties or websites that are not in any of our control and therefore will not be covered by any term of this Privacy Policy terms mentioned on this site i.e. only applicable to PCUtilitiesPro.com. Should you be accessing other websites using any links from our website, these sites can collect private information from your computer which may be used in accordance to their privacy policy, which is different from ours.

##### Cookies for statistics and analytics purposes:

We use cookies here at the PCUtilitiesPro.com website. Cookies are pieces of parts of information sent by a server to a browser which enables a server to get data from the web browser. PCUtilitiesPro.com does not gather any personal data or details from installed cookies. The cookies are used to ensure and enable the sign in process faster and easier for returning users, allowing the site to keep track of any products one has added to their shopping cart, including the preferred geographic location, language preference, and type of currency, enabling to keep track of user movements for statistical information analysis.

##### Correct or Update your personal data:

We here at PCUtilitiesPro.com make available a method for correcting or updating one's personal data from our data records if and when needed at any given point of time once requested by The User. A delay of a few weeks applies to corrections and updates of personal information as PCUtilitiesPro.com attempts to verify the truthful identity of a user requesting such changes to their information prior to it being executed by us. To correct or update personal information, simply send an email to our Customer Service Dept. and we shall be of assistance to remedy the situation as soon as possible. If you no longer wish to be on our mailing list, see our opt-out process as described above.

If you no longer wish to be on our mailing list, see our opt-out process as described above.

##### You should know this: 

You have a right to access the personal data that is held about you. To obtain a copy of the personal information PCUtilitiesPro.com has of you, please send an email to our Customer Service Dept. (in the title, copy and paste this: "Obtain a copy of my personal information").

##### Notification of changes:

You as The User will always be notified should we decide to change this Policy so that you may carry on being secure about your privacy when dealing with us. This Policy was last updated on June 13, 2009. When we decide on updating or modifying our Policy, we always post a notification on our website, PCUtilitiesPro.com, homepage to that effect with a link to the revised Version of the Policy. You shall always be aware of what data and info we gather from our users, how we use it, and under which conditions and terms we may reveal it.

## Feel Free To Contact Us!

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy or if you believe that this website is not following its stated privacy policy, please contact us through our Contact Us page.

The PC Utilities Pro Software Limited Team!
